{"tossups": [{"question": "The inductive effect, which can be used to explain why hydrofluoric acid is a weak acid while the other hydrogen halides are strong acids, is a result of differences in this quantity. High atomic values of this quantity can be used to explain leaving group ability for (*) SN2 reactions. Linus Pauling was the first person to develop a scale of this quantity, which determined it through bond energies. Caesium has the lowest value for this quantity of all of the elements at 0.79. For 10 points, name this quantity which measures how strongly electrons are attracted to the nucleus of a certain element.", "answer": "electronegativity ", "subcategory": "Chemistry", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>electronegativity</u></b>", "acceptable": ["electronegativity"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The battles of Palmito Ranch and Five Forks both took place in this year. During this year, Confederate forces were driven from an assault on Fort Steadman as part of the Siege of Petersburg. A speech given in this year encouraged (*) \u201cmalice towards none\u201d and \u201ccharity for all\u201d to \u201cbind up the nation\u2019s wounds.\u201d Ten days before the start of this year, Savannah was captured by William Tecumseh Sherman as part of his March to the Sea. For 10 points, Abraham Lincoln was assassinated just after Robert E. Lee surrendered at Appomattox in what year?", "answer": "1865 ", "subcategory": "American History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>1865</u></b>", "acceptable": ["1865"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This leader was targeted by the Papal Bull Regnans in Excelsis, and commissioned a fleet that lost the Siege of Corunna and failed to capture and start a revolt in Lisbon. The Nine Years\u2019 War, also known as Tyrone\u2019s Rebellion, took place in Ireland during the rule of this monarch. The (*) Ridolfi Plot and the Babington Plot, the latter of which was exposed by Francis Walsingham, attempted to overthrow this ruler, who claimed they had the \u201cheart and stomach of a king\u201d in a speech given at Tilbury prior to the expected arrival of the Spanish Armada. For 10 points, name this \u201cVirgin Queen\u201d of England, the daughter of Henry VIII and sister of Mary I.", "answer": "Elizabeth I of England ", "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Elizabeth I of England</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Elizabeth I of England"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "One leader of this country declared \u201cno victor, no vanquished\u201d following the end of a civil war, but only gave affected individuals 20 pounds of cash for stolen, seized, or destroyed property. That civil war in this country began after a coup led by the Young Majors and a subsequent countercoup by Yakubu Gowon, leading Emeka Ojukwu to declare the independence of its (*) southeastern region. Doctors Without Borders was formed following a massive famine in Biafra during that civil war in this country. For 10 points, name this country where oil is exported from Port Harcourt and Lagos.", "answer": "Federal Republic of Nigeria ", "subcategory": "World History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "Federal Republic of <b><u>Nigeria</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Federal Republic of Nigeria"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This ruler married the boy Sporus after he allegedly kicked his wife to death, and he built the large Domus Aurea following the destruction of many aristocratic villas in Rome. This ruler arranged the death of his mother (*) Agrippina and was earlier tutored by Seneca the Younger. Boudica\u2019s Rebellion was put down by Suetonius Paulinus during the rule of this emperor, who was targeted by the Pisonian Conspiracy. A rebellion led by Galba led to the overthrow of this emperor in 68 AD, the Year of the Four Emperors. For 10 points, name this emperor who allegedly fiddled during the Great Fire of Rome. ", "answer": "Nero Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus (do not prompt on anything) ", "subcategory": "Ancient History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Nero Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Nero Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "do not prompt on anything"}, {"question": "The cortical reaction is a type of \u201cslow block\u201d that takes place in these cells. After the release of one of these cells, the dominant follicle becomes the corpus luteum. Since these cells are generated in an uneven cell division, they are produced alongside smaller byproducts known as (*) polar bodies. The acrosomes of certain cells are exposed in an effort to bind to the zona pellucida of these cells, whose release is triggered by spikes in FSH and LH levels. A zygote forms from the fusion of these cells with sperm cells in fertilization. For 10 points, name these female reproductive cells.", "answer": "egg cells (or eggs, ova, ovum, or oocytes; prompt on \u201cgametes\u201d) ", "subcategory": "Biology", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>egg cells</u></b>", "acceptable": ["egg cells"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "or eggs, ova, ovum, or oocytes; prompt on \u201cgametes\u201d"}, {"question": "A satellite of this planet is believed to be covered in ice spikes called penitents. Adlinda and Valhalla are multilayer basins on a moon of this planet, another of which is the target of a proposed \u201clander\u201d mission that would complement a (*) \u201cClipper\u201d being sent by the European Space Agency. A moon of this planet has the only known lunar magnetic field in the solar system, and was discovered to contain various oxygen molecules in its atmosphere. The 79 moons of this planet include the Galilean moons of Callisto, Io, Europa, and Ganymede. For 10 points, name this largest planet in the solar system.", "answer": "Jupiter ", "subcategory": "Astronomy", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Jupiter</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Jupiter"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "For one type of ideal surface, the amount of this phenomenon is proportional to the cosine of the angle formed by the wave and the normal vector of the surface. The Lambertian type of this thing models it in an irregular, rough material, its \u201cdiffuse\u201d form. None of this phenomenon occurs at (*) Brewster\u2019s Angle. A law of this phenomenon states that the angle of incidence is equal to the angle of this phenomenon, and the \u201ctotal internal\u201d form of it occurs if the angle of incidence is larger than the critical angle. For 10 points, name this process by which light provides mirror images when interacting with a flat surface.", "answer": "reflection (accept Lambertian reflectance; accept diffuse reflection) ", "subcategory": "Physics", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>reflection</u></b>", "acceptable": ["reflection"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "accept Lambertian reflectance; accept diffuse reflection"}, {"question": "In one poem, this author described themselves as \u201covertired / of the great harvest I myself desired\u201d as they stand on a ladder \u201csticking through a tree / toward heaven still.\u201d This poet described \u201cthe work of hunters\u201d who \u201cwould have the rabbit out of hiding / to please the (*) yelping dogs,\u201d in a poem in which he describes \u201csomething there is that doesn\u2019t love a wall,\u201d though his neighbor says \u201cgood fences make good neighbors.\u201d This poet also described a path that \u201cwas grassy and wanted wear\u201d within a \u201cyellow wood.\u201d For 10 points, name this poet of \u201cAfter Apple-Picking,\u201d \u201cMending Wall,\u201d and \u201cThe Road not Taken.\u201d", "answer": "Robert Frost ", "subcategory": "Poetry", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Robert <b><u>Frost</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Robert Frost"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "After he is told that he \u201chates everybody,\u201d this character retorts that another character\u2019s \u201cdefect\u201d is \u201cwillfully to misunderstand them,\u201d and that his \u201cgood opinion, once lost, is gone forever.\u201d This character is told that a woman was spared concern for him that she \u201cmight have felt\u201d had he \u201cbehaved in a more gentlemanlike manner.\u201d One character says that she could \u201cforgive\u201d this man\u2019s (*) \u201cpride, if he had not mortified mine,\u201d and he eventually pays Wickham to marry Lydia and encourages Bingley to marry Jane. For 10 points, name this love interest of Elizabeth Bennet in Pride and Prejudice.", "answer": "Fitzwilliam Darcy (accept either underlined portion; or Mr. Darcy) ", "subcategory": "Long Fiction", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Fitzwilliam Darcy</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Fitzwilliam Darcy"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "accept either underlined portion; or Mr. Darcy"}, {"question": "In a play from this country, a police inspector punches another character who supposedly blew a raspberry at him, though it was made up by a character who imitates Judge Malipiero. In that play from this country, the Maniac discovers that the Superintendent pushed the title figure out of a window. In another play from this country, rehearsal of (*) Mixing it Up is interrupted by a group of figures who mock the acting company\u2019s portrayal of them. The Child drowns in a fountain and The Boy shoots himself in Six Characters in Search of an Author, a play from this country. For 10 points, name this home country of Dario Fo and Luigi Pirandello.", "answer": "Italy (or the Italian Republic; the first play mentioned is Accidental Death of an Anarchist) ", "subcategory": "Drama", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Italy</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Italy"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "or the Italian Republic; the first play mentioned is Accidental Death of an Anarchist"}, {"question": "In one poem, this author called the reader to \u201cgive me silence, water, hope\u201d and \u201cspeak through my words and my blood.\u201d This poet stated \u201cbut now the hour of revenge falls, and I love you\u201d and described \u201cwhite hills, white (*) thighs\u201d in \u201cBody of a Woman.\u201d In another poem, this poet defined the \u201chard cold hour / which the night fastens to all the timetables\u201d as the \u201chour of departure,\u201d and exclaimed \u201cin you everything sank!\u201d That poem ends a collection that also includes a poem beginning \u201cTonight I can write the saddest lines.\u201d For 10 points, name this poet of The Heights of Machu Picchu and Twenty Love Poems and a Song of Despair.", "answer": "Pablo Neruda ", "subcategory": "Poetry", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Pablo <b><u>Neruda</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Pablo Neruda"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}]}